# KIMBERLY A. WARHOE



Kimberly A. Warhoe is a Technical Consultant with Long International with over 20 years of experience in Web and Windows application design and development using Visual Studio 2013 and Visual Basic 6.0.

She is experienced in report design and development using Microsoft Reporting Services. Kimberly also has extensive database design and development experience using Microsoft SQL Server, Microsoft Access and Oracle software.

She is adept at identifying and implementing the best analytical approach and design methodologies for each project. She strives to assure project goals are met and that scope and development processes meet project requirements and objectives.

#### **EDUCATION**

B.S., Computer Science and Engineering, University of Colorado at Denver, 2002

#### TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Representative U.S. and international technical experience includes:

- Web design and development using ASP.NET, C#, Visual Studio 2013, ASP, HTML, Pearl, JavaScript, VBScript, VBA, Oracle Portal, Ajax Toolkit, Telerik Controls, Web Services, NHibernate, WPF, Facebook API, Twitter API, Website Payments with PayPal API.
- Windows application design and development using VB.Net, Visual Basic 6.0 and report development with Microsoft Reporting Services
- Database experience with Microsoft SQL Server, Microsoft Access and Oracle 10g, TSQL, Stored Procedures, Triggers and LINQ to SQL.

#### PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Ms. Warhoe has worked for the US government and for the private sector developing enterprise software applications that allow users to securely interact with data to track construction projects, take online surveys and update hospital patient records. Representative projects include the following:

- Developer for an internet kiosk application with SQL Server database for the Federal Government. This application allows the clinic administration to manage their kiosks, surveys and patient data in Tacoma, Washington.
- Designed and developed a Windows software solution for project management. This tool allows team members to create, track and maintain task orders related to the SR520 floating bridge construction project in Seattle, Washington.
- Designed and developed software solutions for clients to enhance or modify Sage MAS 500 ERP accounting software in Seattle, Washington.
- Developed an Oracle database and Oracle Portal Website for URS Corporation in Seattle, Washington. This website is used as a marketing tool resource to maintain detailed project data and images for use in proposals for new work. Developed a Microsoft Access desktop application to be used by environmental field technicians to monitor and track all environmental impact sites contained on military bases throughout the country.

# Resume of Kimberly A. Warhoe

Page 2

• Developed an internet document tracking and search tool for a Federal Government entity. This tool is used to save documents and document metadata to a database. Users can then search the metadata related to the documents.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Long International, Inc.

Bainbridge Island, Washington (November 2014 to Present)

As a Technical Consultant with Long International, Ms. Warhoe provides software and database support to the construction industry. She is skilled at developing software that professionals use to enter, track, and maintain detailed metadata for project documentation.

### Federal Government / Madigan Medical Center

Tacoma, Washington (December 2010 to Present)

Senior Team Member developing ASP.Net kiosk application with SQL Server database for Madigan Medical Center. The program was developed in .NET/C# using Telerik Controls, Web Services, and NHibernate with an SQL Server database. This application allows the clinic administration users to have complete control over their kiosks, surveys and patient data. The survey builder portion of the application provides the flexibility to build and use surveys at the clinic level, additionally standardized surveys can be built for use across all clinics within in a hospital setting. Duties also included interacting with the client to collect project requirements and objectives in order to assure project goals, scope and development processes meet requirements and objectives. Developed and maintained project documentation and reports throughout the project lifecycle. Coordinated, with the software testing team, the required testing procedures for the project iteration development process. Maintained testing result documentation during the project lifecycle.

### **Washington State Department of Transportation**

Seattle, Washington (June 2010 to October 2010)

Designed and developed software solutions for a project management tool that allows team members to create, track and maintain task orders related to the US\$4.2 billion WSDOT State Route 520 construction project. The development was done in VB.Net utilizing WPF data grids and controls with data binding to SQL Server Data elements. Mathematical analysis was used to design and develop complex statistical algorithms to process the data to give the end user the necessary results to track their projects according to schedule, budget and impacts. The program allowed for stage approval by key players to be automated and automation of email notifications regarding important stages of the process. Coordinated meetings with the client to collect project requirements and objectives in order to assure project goals, scope and development processes meet requirements and objectives. Developed and maintained project documentation and reports throughout the project lifecycle. Developed and made available on the web, end user documentation that explained the complex features of the software in a concise and understandable way for non-technical users.

### Federal Government/Madigan Medical Center

Tacoma, Washington (January 2010 to June 2010)

Designed and developed .Net kiosk application and SQL Server database for Madigan Army Medical Center. The program was developed in ASP.Net/C# using AJAX Toolkit controls, LINQ to SQL to interact with the SQL Server database. The application provided a patient appointment check-in feature that programmatically checked a patient into their appointment in the CHCS medical records database, which was then reflected in ALTA. The program also provided a patient survey module. The surveys were built

# Resume of Kimberly A. Warhoe

Page 3

at runtime from the database. This feature would allow survey changes to be made in the database, thus preventing the need for code changes to add or change a survey. Coordinated meetings with the client to collect project requirements and objectives in order to assure project goals, scope and development processes met requirements and objectives. Developed and maintained project documentation throughout the project lifecycle.

### The Macabe Associates, LLC

Seattle, Washington (July 2007 to January 2010)

Designed and developed software solutions for clients to enhance or modify Sage MAS 500 ERP accounting software. The development included modifying and creating ActiveX modules with Visual Basic 6.0 and the design and development of relational database solutions.

# **URS** Corporation

Seattle, Washington (September 2006 to April 2007)

Developed an Oracle database and Oracle Portal Website using the Portal Framework, HTML, JavaScript and PL-SQL. The website will be used as a marketing tool resource to maintain detailed project data and images for use in proposals for new work. The site allows the user to search and view the projects in the database, add new projects and edit existing projects.

### **URS** Corporation

Denver, Colorado (April 2005 to July 2006)

Microsoft Access / Visual Basic 6.0 application design and development. Responsible for developing a MS Access desktop application to be used by environmental field technicians to monitor and track all environmental impact sites located on military bases throughout the country. The application allowed the field technicians to easily update and maintain all data associated with each impact.

ASP.NET website design and development team member. Responsible for developing the document tracking tool for the website. As a result, users were able to maintain all electronic and hardcopy documents with this tool. All metadata for each document would be maintained in an SQL Server database. This data was then used to provide an extensive search engine that allowed the users to easily locate all documents related to a specific topic, department, date range etc.

### Wright Water Engineers, Inc.

Denver, Colorado (June 2002 to April 2005)

Designed, developed, and deployed a Visual Basic 6.0 user interface for a database that contained approximately 3,600 address book contacts. The goal for the user interface was to provide a friendly functional tool for a Federal Government client. The contact list utilized Transact-SQL stored procedures to query an SQL Server database. The interface allowed the user to see the data broken down into a variety of lists. The interface also allowed the user to export and import from Microsoft Excel and CSV text files.